Guide to the Pelli Clarke Pelli Architects Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) expansion and renovation (New York, NY) (7701), 1952-2007; Series I
  - Photographic and moving images
    - Final photography
      - Cervin Robinson: proof sheets, Circa 1984 (Box 14, Folder 5)
      - Exterior images, Circa 1984 (Box 14, Folder 5)
      - Interior images, Circa 1984 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Abodia images
      - Set of Abodia slides [some missing], Undated (Box 14, Folder 7)
      - Select Abodia images and transparencies, Undated (Box 14, Folder 8-11)
    - Video footage of MoMA in 1994 [DVD], 1994 December; 7
      - Use copy (Box 65U)
    - Appendix
      - Detailed finding aid prepared by Pelli Clarke Pelli Architects staff, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Spreadsheet of PCPA materials to destroy or donate generated by staff of PCPA, 2005 (Box 8, Folder 26)
- Pre-Cesar Pelli & Associates project records, 1965-1976, 1965-2010; Series II
  - Daniel, Mann, Johnson & Mendenhall [DMJM] projects
    - Universal Studios Exhibition Center
      - 1965 (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Oversized sketch, 1965 (Box 58, Folder 288)
    - Sunset Mountain Park Urban Nucleus, 1965 (Box 47, Folder 2-10)
    - Century City Medical Center, 1966 (Box 47, Folder 11-21)
    - Federal Aviation Administration Regional Headquarters, 1966 (Box 47, Folder 22-29)
    - General Telephone Building Executive Headquarters Offices, 1966 (Box 47, Folder 30-35)
    - Lockheed Burbank, 1966 (Box 47, Folder 36)
    - Lockheed Sunnyvale, 1966 (Box 47, Folder 37-38)
    - Teledyne Labs, 1966 (Box 48, Folder 39-49)
    - Worldway Postal Center, 1966 (Box 48, Folder 50-61)
    - Ala Wai, 1967 (Box 48, Folder 62)
    - Bank of America, 1967 (Box 48, Folder 63)
    - Comsat Laboratories
      - 1967 (Box 48, Folder 64-67)
      - 1967 (Box 49, Folder 68-86)
      - 1967 (Box 50, Folder 87-89)
    - Kukui Gardens Housing
      - 1967-2010 (Box 50, Folder 90-97)
      - 1967 (Box 58, Folder 301)
      - Video statement by Cesar Pelli for 40th anniversary of project, 2010; 7
        - Use copy (Box 66U)
    - Third Street Tunnel Extension ("Bunker Hill Tunnel"), 1967 (Box 50, Folder 98)
    - California Jewelry Mart, 1968 (Box 50, Folder 99)
  - Gruen Associates, 1968-1976
    - General materials
      - Circa 1968 (Box 50, Folder 100)
      - Oversized magazine, Circa 1968 (Box 58, Folder 289)
    - Pacific Centre
      - 1968 (Box 50, Folder 101-106)
      - 1968 (Box 51, Folder 107-111)
      - Oversized marketing booklet, 1968 (Box 58, Folder 290)
    - Beef N' Counter, 1969 (Box 51, Folder 112)
    - Manchester Lease, 1969 (Box 51, Folder 113)
    - San Bernardino City Hall (including designs for bus stop, elderly housing, YMCA, and parking garage)
      - 1969 (Box 51, Folder 114-125)
      - Oversized photographs, 1969 (Box 58, Folder 291-292)
    - Simpson's Court, 1969 (Box 51, Folder 126)
    - U. N. City, International Competition
      - 1969 (Box 51, Folder 127-135)
      - Oversized marketing booklet, 1969 (Box 58, Folder 293)
    - Western Electric/Gateway II, 1969 (Box 52, Folder 136-137)
    - Columbus Commons
      - 1970 (Box 52, Folder 138-158)
      - 1970 (Box 53, Folder 159-172)
      - Oversized materials, 1970 (Box 58, Folder 294-295)
      - Oversized site plan, 1970 (Box 61, Folder 1)
    - Ohrbach's Prototype, 1970 (Box 53, Folder 173-174)
    - Security Pacific National Bank
      - 1970 (Box 53, Folder 175-177)
      - Oversized drawings, 1970 (Box 58, Folder 296)
      - Oversized construction drawings set, 1970 (Box 60, Folder 1)
    - White Front Discount Stores, 1970 (Box 53, Folder 178)
    - Oakland City Center -- Wells Fargo building and Clorox building
      - 1971 (Box 54, Folder 179-191)
      - Oversized photographs, 1971 (Box 58, Folder 297-298)
    - Pacific Design Center, Phase 1, Blue Building
      - 1971 (Box 54, Folder 192-207)
      - 1971 (Box 55, Folder 208-210)
      - Oversized materials, 1971 (Box 58, Folder 299-300)
      - Oversized blueprint drawing sets, 1971 (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - Moscow Trade Center
      - 1972 (Box 55, Folder 211)
      - Presentation box, 1972 (Box 59)
    - Ten Eyck Blocks, 1972 (Box 55, Folder 212)
    - U. S. Embassy, Tokyo
      - 1972 (Box 55, Folder 213-228)
      - 1972 (Box 56, Folder 229-231)
      - Oversized ink on mylar drawings, 1972 (Box 60, Folder 3-4)
      - Oversized bid set drawings, 1972 (Box 62)
    - Fox Hills Mall, 1973 (Box 56, Folder 232-236)
    - Zurich American Insurance Company, 1973 (Box 56, Folder 237)
    - Lauritsen Laboratory, 1974 (Box 56, Folder 238)
    - Rainbow Center Mall/Wintergarden, 1975 (Box 56, Folder 239-250)
    - Biennale House
      - 1976 (Box 56, Folder 251-260)
      - 1976 (Box 57, Folder 261-274)
    - Daehan Kyoyuk Insurance Company
      - 1976 (Box 57, Folder 275-286)
      - 1976 (Box 60, Folder 2)
    - Beaumont Civic Center, Undated (Box 57, Folder 287)
- Project records, Circa 1975-2005; Series III
  - U.S. Embassy Cuba, 1977 (Havana, Cuba) (7702), 1977-1978
    General
    This is an unbuilt project.
    - Detailed finding aid prepared by Pelli Clarke Pelli Architects Staff, Undated (Box 89, Folder 128)
    - Design requirements, 1978 (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - Photographic images, Havana and Old Embassy, 1977 December and undated (Box 70, Folder 2-5)
    - Oversized drawings, 1977 (Box 79)
      Scope and Contents
      Facade perspectives; elevation studies; stair studies; exterior perimeter fence studies; assorted drawings.
  - Oliver Tyrone, 1978 (Pittsburgh, PA) (7810)
    - Detailed finding aid prepared by Pelli Clarke Pelli Architects Staff, Undated (Box 89, Folder 128)
    - Project descriptions, Undated (Box 70, Folder 6)
    - Original sketches by Cesar Pelli, Undated (Box 70, Folder 7)
    - Design images, drawings and models, Undated (Box 70, Folder 8-11)
    - Pittsburgh images, Undated (Box 70, Folder 12-13)
  - Pin Oak Master Plan and Pin Oak One, 1979-1983 (Houston, TX) (7903/8021)
    - Detailed finding aid prepared by Pelli Clarke Pelli Architects Staff, Undated (Box 89, Folder 128)
    - Marketing book, 1981 February (Box 70, Folder 14)
    - Project descriptions, project data, and press clippings, 1982 and undated (Box 70, Folder 15)
    - Images of Cesar, Fred, and office, Undated (Box 70, Folder 16)
    - Design images, models and site images, Undated (Box 70, Folder 17-23)
    - Design photographs, drawings and models, 1982 and undated (Box 70, Folder 24-28)
    - Design photographs, models, 1982 and undated (Box 74, Folder 29-31)
    - Photographic images, models, 1980-1981 and undated (Box 78, Folder 110-112)
    - Project directory, schedule, file and drawings organization, Undated (Box 78, Folder 113)
    - Contracts and agreements, 1981 March-1982 March (Box 89, Folder 114)
    - Program (Box 89, Folder 115)
    - Correspondence, 1980 November-1982 June (Box 89, Folder 116-118)
    - Progress reports, 1981 October-1982 April (Box 89, Folder 119)
    - Client-Architect meeting minutes, 1980 October-1982 March (Box 89, Folder 120)
    - Notes of in-house reviews, 1980 November-1982 April (Box 89, Folder 121)
    - Telephone memos, 1980 December-1983 July (Box 89, Folder 122)
    - Core studies, 1981 September (Box 89, Folder 123)
    - Area calculations, 1981 October-1982 January and undated (Box 89, Folder 124)
    - SK Studies, 1981 September-1982 April (Box 89, Folder 125)
    - Specifications, 1981 November-1982 March (Box 89, Folder 126)
    - Model materials, Circa 1981 (Box 89, Folder 127)
    - Oversized Drawings, 1979-1981 (Box 80)
      Conceptual site plan; presentaion renderings; plans, sections, and elevations; axonometric site plans; tower top.
    - Oversized Drawings, 1982 (Box 88)
      Final design development set A1-A32 and unnumbered drawings.
    - Concept and preliminary sketches, 1980-1981
      Conditions Governing Access
      [Computer files]
    - Concept and preliminary sketches, 1980-1981
  - Four Leaf Towers, 1979-1982 (Houston, TX) (7905), 1979-1983
    - Detailed finding aid prepared by Pelli Clarke Pelli Architects Staff, Undated (Box 89, Folder 128)
    - Project descriptions, data, and bibliography, 1979 and undated (Box 74, Folder 32)
    - Marketing materials, 1982 and undated (Box 74, Folder 33-34)
    - Press clippings, 1980-1983 (Box 74, Folder 35)
    - Sketch of towers, Undated (Box 74, Folder 36)
    - Images of Cesar and client, 1979 December-1981 March (Box 74, Folder 37-38)
    - Drawings, elevations and floor plans, 1979 and undated (Box 74, Folder 39)
    - Design images, Undated (Box 74, Folder 40-42)
      Renderings and plans; floor plans; models.
    - Photographic images, design models, Undated (Box 74, Folder 43)
    - Construction images, 1980-1981 and undated (Box 74, Folder 44-45)
    - Final photography, 1982 July and undated (Box 74, Folder 46-50)
      Contact sheets; exterior and interior; details; slides.
    - Oversized drawings, 1979 (Box 71)
      Landscape site plan; design development set and MEP set.
    - Oversized drawings, Circa 1979 (Box 72)
      Site and floor plans; tower top studies and drawings; exterior and interior elevations.
    - Oversized drawings, Circa 1979 (Box 73)
      Elevations and curtain wall drawings; study elevations of lobby; lobby floor pattern studies; miscellaneous lobby studies.
  - Private Residence in Maryland, First Site, 1979-1999 (Maryland, US) (7906), 1979-1981
    Records are restricted until 2033. Researchers who wish to access these records must received permission from Pelli Clarke Pelli Architects.
    See also: Private Residence in Maryland, First Site, 1984-1999 (8410/8507)
    - Detailed finding aid prepared by Pelli Clarke Pelli Architects Staff, Undated (Box 94, Folder 1)
    - Preliminary sketches by Cesar Pelli and Fred Clarke, Circa 1979 (Box 94, Folder 1)
    - Photographic images: CP sketches, drawings, models and site, Circa 1979 (Box 94, Folder 2-7)
    - Administrative files: correspondence, meetings minutes, notes, program, consultant files, 1979-1981 (Box 94, Folder 8-15)
    - Administrative and design files: detail drawings (SKs) and specifications, 1979-1980 (Box 95, Folder 16-20)
    - Drawings: topographic surveys, schematic plans, presentation drawings, axonometric studies, 1979-1980 (Box 103)
    - Contract drawing set on mylar, 1981 (Box 104)
  - Four Stamford Forum, 1979-1987 (Stamford, CT) (7908/8317)
    - Detailed finding aid prepared by Pelli Clarke Pelli Architects Staff, Undated (Box 89, Folder 128)
    - Project descriptions and press clippings, 1979 and undated (Box 75, Folder 51)
    - Images of Cesar, Undated (Box 75, Folder 52)
    - Design images, models, Undated (Box 75, Folder 53-54)
    - Photographic images, 1979 Jul, 1986 September and undated (Box 75, Folder 55-57)
      Construction and curtain wall; site; exterior and interior.
    - Correspondence, 1983-1987
      - Contract-related, 1979-1986 (Box 75, Folder 58)
      - 1979-1980 (Box 75, Folder 62)
      - 1982 (Box 75, Folder 63)
      - 1983 May-September (Box 75, Folder 64)
      - 1983 Oct-Dec (Box 76, Folder 65)
      - 1984 (Box 76, Folder 66-69)
      - 1985 (Box 76, Folder 70-73)
      - 1986 and 1987 September (Box 76, Folder 74)
    - Contracts (Box 75, Folder 59)
    - Specifications (Box 75, Folder 60-61)
    - Oversized drawings, 1980 (Box 81)
    - Oversized drawings, 1980-1985 (Box 82)
    - Oversized drawings, 1979-1980 (Box 83)
  - Hermann Park Towers, 1979-1980 (Houston, TX) (7909)
    - Detailed finding aid prepared by Pelli Clarke Pelli Architects Staff, Undated (Box 89, Folder 128)
    - Project descriptions and project data, Undated (Box 77, Folder 75)
    - Correspondence, 1979 August-1981 January (Box 77, Folder 76)
    - Press clippings, 1981 and undated (Box 77, Folder 77)
    - Photographic images, 1979 November and undated (Box 77, Folder 78-81)
      Drawings, elevation studies, renderings, sketches, sections, floor plans, and models.
    - Design files, drawings and elevation studies, 1980 February (Box 77, Folder 82)
    - Oversized drawings, 1979-1980 (Box 85)
      Schematic design presentation quality renderings and drawings; exterior elevations, sections, and details; plans.
  - State Office Building, 1979 (Sacramento, CA) (7910), 1979-1981 (Box 77, Folder 83-84)
    - Detailed finding aid prepared by Pelli Clarke Pelli Architects Staff, Undated (Box 89, Folder 128)
    - Project description and photographic images, Undated (Box 77, Folder 83)
    - Photographic images, 1981 February-May and undated (Box 77, Folder 84)
  - Bunker Hill Office Tower, 1979-1980 (Los Angeles, CA) (7911)
    - Detailed finding aid prepared by Pelli Clarke Pelli Architects Staff, Undated (Box 89, Folder 128)
    - Project descriptions and fact sheets, Undated (Box 77, Folder 85)
    - Business development, proposal materials, 1979-1980 (Box 77, Folder 86)
    - Original drawings by Cesar Pelli, 1979 November (Box 77, Folder 87)
    - Concept sketches
    - Design files, Undated (Box 77, Folder 88-89)
      Elevations, sections, plans, and area studies.
    - Photographic images, 1979 and undated (Box 77, Folder 90-93)
      Models, drawings, and plans.
    - Press clippings, 1979 October-1982 March (Box 78, Folder 94-95)
    - Oversize marketing book, 1980 (Box 86)
    - Concept sketches, Undated
  - 900 Third Avenue, 1979-1983 (New York, NY) (7912), 1979-1986
    - Detailed finding aid prepared by Pelli Clarke Pelli Architects Staff, Undated (Box 89, Folder 128)
    - Project descriptions and fact sheets, 1980-1986 and undated (Box 78, Folder 96)
    - Design research and calculations, 1980 and undated (Box 78, Folder 97)
    - Sketches and schematic design studies, Circa 1979-1981 September (Box 78, Folder 98-101)
    - Photographic images, 1979-1982 (Box 78, Folder 102-107)
      Site; models and drawings; Construction; final and Abidia slides.
    - Press clippings and ads, 1980 May-1981 August and undated (Box 78, Folder 108)
    - Oversized drawings, 1979-1980 (Box 87)
      Renderings; schematic design presentaion quality renderings and drawing set; elevation drawing.
    - Oversized drawings, Circa 1980 (Box 90)
      Elevations; presentation plans, sections, and elevations.
    - Concept sketches, Circa 1979
  - Private Residence in Maryland, Final Site, 1984-1999 (Maryland, US) (8410/8507), 1984-1989
    See also: Private Residence in Maryland, First Site, 1979-1981 (7906)
    - Detailed finding aid prepared by Pelli Clarke Pelli Architects Staff, Undated (Box 94, Folder 1)
    - General
      - Project statements by Cesar Pelli, Circa 1987 (Box 95, Folder 21)
      - Original drawing by Cesar Pelli, Circa 1987 (Box 95, Folder 22)
      - Public relations files: project descriptions and fact sheets, correspondence, notes, press clippings, 1987-1999 (Box 95, Folder 23-25)
    - Photographic images
      - Images of Cesar Pelli and client, drawings, models, construction, Circa 1984-1989 (Box 95, Folder 26-34)
      - Final photography, site images, abodia and miscellaneous, Circa 1984-1989 (Box 96, Folder 35-42)
    - Administrative files
      - Contract, 1986 (Box 96, Folder 43)
      - Outgoing correspondence, 1985-1987 (Box 96, Folder 44-49)
      - Outgoing correspondence, 1988-1989 and undated (Box 97, Folder 50-58)
      - Incoming correspondence, 1985-1987 (Box 98, Folder 59-70)
      - Incoming correspondence, 1988-1989 and undated (Box 99, Folder 71-77)
      - Meeting minutes, 1985-1987 (Box 99, Folder 78-84)
      - Meeting minutes, 1987-1989 and undated (Box 100, Folder 85-92)
      - Telephone notes, 1986-1988 (Box 100, Folder 93-103)
      - Telephone notes, 1988-1989 and undated (Box 101, Folder 104-107)
      - Notes, 1985-1989 and undated (Box 101, Folder 108)
      - Chronological files: sitework/landscaping, lighting, kitchen, stone, laundry room, elevator, acoustics, dining room, security, 1985-1989 (Box 101, Folder 109-117)
      - Certificate and terms of substantial completion, 1988 (Box 102, Folder 118)
      - Accessory buildings: correspondence, specifications, notes, cost estimates, 1988-1989 (Box 102, Folder 131-134)
    - Drawings
      - Site and overall building
        - Preliminary and schematic design drawings: plans and sections, 1984 July-1985 April (Box 105, Folder 1-13)
        - Schematic design drawings: plans, sections, elevations, Circa 1984-1985 (Box 106)
        - Schematic design floor plans, Circa 1984-1985 (Box 102, Folder 119)
        - Schematic design drawing set (final plan): plans and sections, 1985 April-June (Box 106)
        - Schematic design elevation studies, Circa 1985 (Box 108)
        - Elevation studies north-south (final plan), Circa 1985 (Box 108)
        - Color elevation studies (colored pencil on architectural reproductions), Circa 1984-1985 (Box 107)
        - Site and landscaping plans, 1985 December (Box 109)
        - Assorted design development drawings (unnumbered, dated), 1985 July - 1986 February (Box 111)
        - Contract drawing set (original drawings on Mylar), 1985-1987 (Box 110)
        - Mini contract drawing set (prints), 1985-1987 (Box 112, Folder 1-3)
        - Presentation-quality rendering of south elevation (Stabilo pencil on Mylar), Circa 1989 (Box 108)
      - Pavilions, Entrances and Spine
        - Stair tower and elevator pavilion studies: plans, sections, elevations, 1985 August (Box 112, Folder 4)
        - Stair tower and garage studies: plans, sections, elevations and perspective drawings, 1985 September-October and undated (Box 109)
        - Kitchen and dining pavilion studies, 1985 September and undated (Box 109)
        - Kitchen and dining pavilion studies, Circa 1985 (Box 102, Folder 120)
        - Entrance elevation studies, Circa 1985 (Box 108)
        - Assorted pavilion elevation studies, Circa 1985 (Box 108)
        - Spine roofline studies: sections, Circa 1985 (Box 112, Folder 5)
        - Spine elevation studies, Circa 1985 (Box 108)
        - Master bath, guest room and maid's room studies, 1985 September (Box 105, Folder 14)
        - Sections at spine, living room pavilion, kitchen/dining pavilion looking west, stairway/elevator and garage door showing wall details, Circa 1985-1986 (Box 111)
        - Upper spine hallway and sitting area studies: plans, elevations, perspectives includes details of shelving, Circa 1986 (Box 111)
      - Details
        - Architectural detail drawings (numbered SKs) of interior and exterior features includes: doors, steps and walkways, closets, custom shelves and furnishings, pergola, mechanical details, 1986-1989 (Box 112, Folder 6-7)
        - Architectural detail drawings (numbered SKs), 1986-1988 and undated (Box 102, Folder 121-130)
        - Architectural detail drawings (unnumbered, some dated) includes: shelving, kitchen cabinets, elevator cab, doors, mailbox, security grills, 1986-1989 and undated (Box 113)
        - Stair detail studies: sections and elevations, 1985 October-December (Box 112, Folder 8)
        - Bathroom hall skylight studies, 1985 October (Box 112, Folder 9)
        - Fountain concept sketches, 1986 February (Box 112, Folder 10)
        - Floor studies: spine and living room pavilion, Circa 1986-1988 (Box 111)
        - Living room fireplace details, 1988 and undated (Box 113)
        - Dining room table: plans, elevations and details, 1988-1989 (Box 111)
        - Mechanical equipment enclosure S1, A1-A3, 1989 July (Box 112, Folder 11)
        - Spine table studies: axonometrics, elevations, 1989 (Box 112, Folder 12-13)
        - Planter studies, Circa 1988-1989 (Box 113)
        - Pergola studies, Circa 1988-1989 (Box 111)
      - Accessory buildings
        - Accessory buildings drawings, 1987-1988 (Box 102, Folder 135-137)
        - Accessory buildings final drawing set, includes detail drawings and studies, 1988-1989 (Box 113)
  - Proposed Office Building, 1979 (Denver, CO) (Box 78, Folder 109)
    Two 35mm slides and one 8x10" photographic print of renderings.
  - Yale University Music Center campus master plan and building [project] (New Haven, CT) (8109), Circa 1975-1981
    - Drawings, 1980-1981 (Box 63)
    - Portfolio with clipping and letter, Circa 1975 (Box 67)
  - Vogelstein Center for Drama and Film, Vassar College (Poughkeepsie, NY) (9919) and National Museum of Osaka (Osaka, Japan) (9520), Circa 2003-2005; 25839.89
- Computer files (Box 114–117)
  Original born digital files, as well as preservation masters, may not be accessed due to their fragility. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist request that they be made. Born digital files cannot be accessed remotely. System requirements include a Manuscripts and Archives computer and file viewing software.